# Subhashis Phani

5-53/2A, Laxminagar Colony Old Alwal, Secunderabad Pin:500010 Ph: +918826997831 email: subhashispin@gmail.com

## **PROFILE**

Chief Financial Officer with more than 27 years of experience directing and improving corporate financial operations of reputed Indian companies. Exceptional skills in developing and implementing processes and controls, improving business operations, and establishing automated financial and business systems. Expertise in re-organizing financial groups and programs to increase performance. Outstanding communication and analytical skills.

## **CORE COMPETENCIES**

- Ability to direct, manage and supervise the financial operations of a large Federal organization or agency, including the development of budget plans, policies, and procedures.
  - Comprehensive knowledge and understanding of all financial processes and compliances.
  - Proven ability to increase profitability and reduce losses.
  - Exercise a high degree of discretion, mature judgment, and tact in handling issues of a sensitive nature.
  - Strong leadership, problem-solving, planning, team-building, and project management skills.

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

#### **Head of Finance & Accounts**

November 2017 to Present

Name of Organization:

**ECOBOARD INDUSTRIES LTD, Pune** 

Successfully Negotiated for stressed Assets restructuring

- Orchestrated budget process with all departments and senior management concluding in the presentation of a final budget approved by the and Board of Directors.
  - · Coordinated actions of auditors at multiple sites and resolved problems occurring during audits
  - Managed the accounting and finance department as well as accounting, tax and audit consultants.
  - Developed and authored Business and Financial plan.
  - Advised CFO on all contracts with third parties including those regarding strategic partnerships.
  - Represented company in numerous presentations in various forums and speaking engagements to business groups.
  - Assessed and implemented a finance organization structure to support the company's effort.
  - Designed and implemented an annual budget process that supported a 5-year plan.
  - Performed financial and productivity reporting, updated forecasting, and report analyses for annual and monthly budget process.
  - · Annual Reports, Directors Report, ROC Charges retrievals. Compliances, GST, Sales Tax assessments etc,
  - Raised funds through alternative channel for smoothening operations of the company
  - Handled Investor relations well.

## **VP Financial Operations**

June 2016 to November 2017

Name of Organization:

Sandstone Infratech, Hyderabad

- Recruited and trained staff and upgraded financial and administrative infrastructure to meet the requirements of real estate start up company based out of Hyderabad
- Hired and managed geographically dispersed staff of differing cultures and weaved them in teams.
- Initiated and developed in-house training department that enabled timely and cost-effective delivery of end-user training.

- Orchestrated budget process with all departments and senior management concluding in the presentation of a final budget approved by the CEO and Board of Directors.
- · Coordinated actions of auditors at multiple sites and resolved problems occurring during audits

## Consultancy

Aug 2015 to June 2016

- Managed the accounting and finance department as well as accounting, tax and audit consultants.
- Developed and authored Business and Financial plan.
- Advised CFO on all contracts with third parties including those regarding strategic partnerships.
- Represented company in numerous printed articles in various periodicals and speaking engagements to business groups. Like ISAP, Delhi, Unnati Fortune Group, Noida

Homestead Infrastructure Development Pvt Ltd

Nov 2012 to Aug 2015

## General Manager (F&A)

Name of Organization:

# Homestead Infrastructure Development Pvt Ltd,

# Gurgaon

- Served as a member of the executive committee and the SAP steering committee and Implementation team
- Achieved balance sheet creditability through establishing accounting policies and procedures.
- Assessed and implemented a finance organization structure to support the company's effort.
- Designed and implemented an annual budget process that supported a 5-year plan.
- Performed financial and productivity reporting, updated forecasting, and report analyses for annual and monthly budget process.
- Successful in raising Debt for Real Estate Project of Michel Schumarker World Tower at sector 109 Gurgaon from Bank of Baroda to the tune of Rs.50 Crs

## Lanco Infratech Limited, Gurgaon

Nov 2007 to Nov 2012

# **Deputy General Manager (MIS and Budgeting)**

Name of Organization:

# Lanco Infratech Limited, Gurgaon

- · Worked in Perth Australia, Griffin Coal Mine in MIS and KT and Back Office in Gurgaon
- Preparation of financial analyses and models to assist in the evaluation of business initiatives, capital investments, new services and programs within Brookes and Brookes business units.
- Innovating reporting structure for Audit Committee Meetings and BOD Meetings of Corporate MIS
- Key Member of Lanco Group FP &A team, budgeting and MIS
- Financial Modelling and Analysis
- Spearheading the preparation of BI/BO Reports and Audit Committee reports for Consumption of Top Management and Independent Auditors.
- Risk Reporting and mitigation follow up and policy follow up with various SPVs and parent company
- Financial Modelling of Lanco Hills, Power SPVs and their updates

## MW Zander SGP India Ltd

March 2007 to Nov 2007

# DGM (F&A)

- Anchoring MIS Reporting to Singapore on a monthly basis in IFRS format for the entire Indian operations
- HOD of Finance and Accounts Team of India, anchored the preparation of Financial Information for the entire Indian operations
- Statutory Audit, Internal Audit of the group for Indian operations
- Filing of periodical TDS, Service Tax Returns for the Indian operations and completing assessments for previous years
- SAP end to end solutions for sychronisation with IFRS reporting structure

#### **IVRCL** Infrastructures & Projects Limited

## Assistant General Manager (F&A), Risk

March 1997 to Feb 2007

- Served as an active part of Water Pipeline Project
- Proactively formulated & implemented systems & procedures while setting up of company
- Successfully managed the materials/inventory worth Rs. 100 crores
- Proficiently devised & enforced MIS systems/procedures for a new branch at Water Divisional Office
- Efficiently handled the complete MIS/progress report for two most prestigious projects for Gujarat Water Infrastructure Ltd., GWSSB & GWRDC, incentivized with team.
- Managing the Financial operations and accounting of various projects, financial reporting of Gujarat Regional Office to Head Office in Hyderabad on aperiodic basis.

- Handling Sub-contractors and vendor payments for all Project of Gujarat Infrastructure Projects. Actively
  involved in the formation of the water division in Hyderabad head office.
- Actively involved in tendering process of prospective Water Projects for company, by conducting financial feasibility and arranging BG's and LC's for bulk purchases and earnest money, working capital through bankers.
- Risk Reporting of Projects in Water Division
- Advisory of Taxation Matters to Water Division Projects

Formative Years April 1990 to Feb 1997

Worked as Accounts Manager for **Om Garments (p) Ltd** in Bangalore, learned the intricacies of taxation, Financial Analysis, Reporting, compliances in **JD Kabra and Co, Hyderabad** a Chartered Accountant Firm, Learned Costing of ERW Steel Pipes and Yarns with **Futnani Steels (P) Ltd and Atlantic Spg & Wvg Mills, Goa**.

### **EDUCATION**

Ramakrishna Mission Vidyamandir, Belur (CALCUTTA UNIVERSITY)

1986

#### **BSc. Mathematics**

Indian Institute of Management Studies, Delhi

1987

#### **PGDBM**

#### **ADDITIONAL SKILLS**

- · Financial Reporting, MIS and Budgeting
- SWOT Analysis
- · Management Accounting
- Client Relationship Management
- Internal Control & Audit
- Financial Advice & Counseling
- SAP FI/CO
- Restructuring &CDR

- · Investor Relations Skills
- Operations & Financial Analysis
- · Record Keeping
- Financial Account Analysis
- Debt Financing & Project Financing
- Financial Leadership
- International Corporate Finance

#### **CERTIFICATIONS**

· Real Estate Modelling Class, Terrapin SGP

• QMS (ISO 9000) Certification

2008

2002

### **PROFESSIONAL AFFILIATIONS**

· Member, Institute of Cost Accountants of India

1990

#### **REFERENCES**

Available upon request